# **Daniel Ussa**

### Rust Engineer & Blockchain Web3 Developer

A highly-skilled, self-motivated and task-driven professional with 11 years of experiences in software development and 5 years of experiences in blockchain development in the sphere of Ethereum, EVM chains, Solana, Cosmos, Polkadot, Aptos and Sui blockchains. Rust and C++ Engineer, who have worked for big projects. Maintain good relationships with team members and leads the team atmosphere in a global team of diverse cultures. (be flexible with work time zone) Always sensitive to new technologies and is not afraid to learn new technology, ignoring all experiences for better solutions.



hightop.dev.hk@gmail.com

2412 Weston Rd, Toronto, Canada

S live:.cid.bee547f7afef24ef

+1 678 999 4503

in linkedin.com/in/daniel-ussa-566262280

github.com/hightop0924

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Rust/Move & Solidity Engineer OPTIFINANCE

08/2021 - 10/2023 Remote, New York, NY

OPTIFINANCE is a member of the UK Financial Conduct Authority (FCA) Innovation Pathways programme. The FCA Innovation Pathways programme helps firms with new business models to launch innovative products and services by understanding how financial regulation relates to their activities

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Raised \$800,000 in first IDO, ensuring high security and excellent quality of the MVP
- Developed 7 swap and staking dApps, earnt \$400,000 using cosmwasm and solidity smart contracts.
- Built ONFT & OFT bridge platform, funded \$80,000 using LayerZero on 10 Evm chains and Aptos.
- Developed 20 move smart contracts of IDO launchpad and coin staking and built a mee-apt swap by using hippo aggregator swap in aptos ecosystem.
- Co-worked with frontend/backend engineers in the agile environment.
- Took part in 10+ Sui Move Challenges which was held during Sui Event in Vietnam.
- Developed Hyperlane Bridge Relayer to support Aptos and Sui using Rust.

Contact: Lev Wang, CTO at EarthShepards

# Rust & Solidity Developer IDEASOFT

03/2018 - 08/2021 Montreal, Canad

IdeaSoft.io is a software development firm that offers custom software development, blockchain, and web development services to their clients in the IT, business services, and education industries.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Raised \$200,000 in first IDO and \$100,000 in NFT sale after developing solana Rust program for IDO launchpad and NFT staking platform.
- Developed bots for crypto trading arbitrage, sandwich trading, and snipping, resulting in earnings exceeding \$100k.
- Collaborated effectively with team members to facilitate discussions on the appropriate direction for the platform.
- Research about building company's own chain using Cosmos SDK on cosmos ecosystem and using Polkadot PDK as a parachain.

### Rust/C++ Backend Developer EXPERTIME OPEN

03/2015 - 03/2018

HONG KONG, Hong Kong

Expertime Open, a software development company, is located in HONG KONG, Hong Kong. The small agency was established in 2014. Their services include custom software development, ecommerce development, mobile app development, web design, and more.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Developed Rust backend chatting-server, gathered 100,000 users using Rust and various DBs such as Postgres, MongoDB, Neo4J and Redis.
- Contributed Binance.com backend, speed up server 30% using Rust FFI.
- Migrated the backend code from express.js into using Rust Axum framework to develop high-scalable web backend service for flexible gaming.

# **EDUCATION**

# Computer Science & IT Lingnan University

03/2008 - 03/2011 8 Castle Peak Rd - Lingnan, Tuen Mun, Hong Kong

# **ACHIEVEMENTS**

# \$80,000 in ONFT & OFT Platform at OPTIFINANCE (02/2023)

Built ONFT and OFT token bridge on 10 Evm chains(Ethereum, BSC, Polygon, Optimism, etc...) and Aptos chain using LayerZero.

#### \$800,000 in First IDO at OPTIFINANCE (11/2022)

While working in OPTIFINANCE, I played a crucial role in facilitating the company's successful First IDO, leveraging my development speed and ensuring the project's high quality, resulting in a raised amount of \$800,000.

#### \$200,000 in NFT sale at IDEASOFT (04/2021)

Led the NFT staking project, which resulted in raising \$200,000 in NFT sale at Magic Eden

#### \$800,000 in Fundraising at IDEASOFT (07/2020)

While working in IDEASOFT, I helped the company not miss the best time for fundraising by finalizing development in time, and it resulted in raising of \$800,000

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

#### Blockchains:

Ethereum, EVM chains, BSC, Solana, Cosmos, Pokadot, Aptos, Sui

#### **Programming Languages:**

Rust, Move, Python, Go, C++, HTML, CSS, Javascript

#### Frameworks:

Diesel, Tokio, ActiX, STL, Boost, Node.js, React.js/Next.js, Express.js/Nest.js, ActixWeb, Axum, Yew

#### **Databases:**

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Redis, Neo4J

### Methodologies:

Scrum, Extreme Programming, Agile, Unified Process, UML

#### Tools:

Docker, Kubernetes, Terraform, AWS, Github, Jira, Trello

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Python/C++ Developer ZHUHAI AIPUJING SOFTWARE CO.

01/2012 - 03/2015

Sheung Wan, Hong Kong

APJ has obtained a series of international qualification standard certifications such as CMMI L5, ISO 9001:2000 and ISO 27001, won many honors such as national high-tech enterprise certification, and was elected as the chairman unit of Zhuhai Service Outsourcing Industry Association.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Optimized performance and scalability of backend service by implementing caching, load balancing, and other best practices.
- Rewrite 5+ WebSocket chat program from JavaScript to Python to achieve high concurrency.
- Write codes for performance-critical part of a game and compiled to WebAssembly to integrate to WebGL and achieved significant performance improvements compared to using pure JavaScript
- Built graphql authorization, depth limiting, cost analysis, rate and directive limiting using Rust and integrated it with apollo router

Contact: René Lacerte - CEO of Bill.com

# **Python/C++ Internship** ZHUHAI AIPUJING SOFTWARE CO.

01/2011 - 01/2012

Sheung Wan, Hong Kong

APJ has obtained a series of international qualification standard certifications such as CMMI L5, ISO 9001:2000 and ISO 27001, won many honors such as national high-tech enterprise certification, and was elected as the chairman unit of Zhuhai Service Outsourcing Industry Association.

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Developed and maintained C++ code for 15 large-scale, high-frequency trading platforms used by 62 financial institutions to trade equities, futures, and FX, successfully recorded zero downtime in 5 years.
- Deployed Python extensively for data analysis tasks including building statistical models of market behavior based on historical data, improved sales by \$25M in the first 10 months.
- Cut memory usage by ~65% through improved coding practices and algorithm optimization, increasing the ability to run 25 intensive applications simultaneously with < 1% lag.</li>

## **CONFERENCES & COURSES**

Educative.io (02/2021 - Present)

Conference/Issuer of the certificate

# **ORGANIZATIONS**

CoinMonks - India's biggest online publication that features articles related blockchain technlogy, which is maintained by blockchain experts and enthusiasts. (12/2021 - Present)

# **LANGUAGES**

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Chinese

Native or Bilingual Proficiency

## **INTERESTS**



Solving Problems



Reading Tech Books



**Cutting-Edge Technology** 



Programming



Geometry



Mathematics



Drawing



Music



Tennis